Weslley Victor da Costa Vieira

Porto, Portugal +351 912 018 056 w3slley.victor@gmail.com

w3slley.github.io







ABOUT ME

I utilize technologies such as JavaScript, Node.js, PHP and MySQL to build and deploy full-stack web applications, having previous experience with Digital Ocean's VPS and the Heroku cloud platform. Given my background in a STEM field, I also have experience with data analysis using tools such as Python and SQL. I'm passionate about learning and I have a special interest in back-end web development and DevOps.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming languages: C/C++ (familiar), Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, PHP

Front-end development: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4, jQuery Back-end development: Node.js, Express, Laravel

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Data analysis: pandas, numpy, matplotlib, SQL

Version Control: Git, GitHub, GitLab

LANGUAGES

Portuguese (Native) English (Fluent) German (Beginner) Spanish (Beginner)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer at Kompetenza

May 2021 – Present

- ✓ Development of integrations between third party applications/APIs and the Salesforce platform
- ✓ Used JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB, Heroku, Apex, Flow Builder, Process Builder, among others

Full-Stack Developer at Accio

Mar 2021 - Present

- ✓ Part of the development team responsible for the implementation of new features on the product
- \checkmark Implemented the MVC software design pattern on back-end code and simple DevOps practices on deployment process
- ✓ Used PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery and Semantic UI

Research Assistant at CAUP

Feb 2020 - Dec 2020

- ✓ Implemented a Python software using statistical tools such as Markov chain Monte Carlo to improve measurement of uncertainties on velocities of stars with the goal of setting constrains on dark matter present on ultra-faint dwarf galaxies
- ✓ Utilized the following Python libraries: numpy, pandas, matplotlib and astropy, among others

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Personal blog

GitHub | Website

- \checkmark Developed a personal blog and deployed it on the Heroku cloud platform.
- \checkmark Utilized Node.js and Express in the back-end, and MySQL as the database.
- ✓ Used *handlebars* as the template engine.
- \checkmark Implemented the MVC design pattern across the application.
- ✓ Code highlighting was implemented with *PrismJs* and support for mathematical notation (LaTeX) was implemented with *MathJax*.

Kino

GitHub | Website

- ✓ Developed a web application where users can look up detailed information about the movies they love.
- ✓ Used Node.js, Express, MongoDB and React for development and it was deployed on Heroku.
- ✓ Project won 1st place at a <u>career fair contest</u> in the back-end development category.

Wikipedia Covid-19 Charts Generator

GitHub

- ✓ Developed a Python script that parses the DGS website for daily Covid-19 reports and generates timeline charts and summary tables with the goal of contributing to Portugal's Wikipedia page.
- ✓ Beautiful Soup, requests and urllib were used to find and download the reports.
- ✓ pdfminer was used to extract data from the PDF files and pandas was used for the data handling.
- ✓ Used pytest for unit testing.

Endenda Mais

GitHub | Website

- ✓ Implemented the website for a science communication project called Entenda Mais.
- ✓ It has CRUD functionalities and readers can leave comments on each article.
- ✓ The project was developed using the PHP framework Laravel and MySQL.

EDUCATION

Universidade do Porto

2018 – 2021 (expected)

Major: Bachelor's Degree in Physics

Minor: Computer Science

CS Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Algorithm Design and Analysis, Web Technologies, Software Architecture, Computer Networking, Databases, Operating Systems, Functional Programming